Aaditi Agarwal

aaditiagarwal1234@gmail.com | (+91) 8979256110 | LinkedIn Profile

Summary

Software developer with over 7 years of experience in Java, bringing a wealth of expertise and a strong commitment to excellence in every project undertaken. Actively seeking opportunities that foster growth, enabling utilization of analytical and technical skills to effectively guide projects, driving both personal and organizational progress.

Skills

- Languages: Java, SpringBoot, RESTful APIs, SQL, Angular
- Technologies & Tools: Git, Jira, ServiceNow, DBeaver, Docker, Agile methodologies

Experience

Jr. IT Manager, ArcelorMittal Design & Engineering Centre – India

Mar 2023 - Feb 2024

- Crafted comprehensive project plans detailing scope and timelines.
- Led cross-functional teams, ensuring strategic alignment and synergy.
- Orchestrated project meetings, distilling key insights and actionable steps.
- Identified and mitigated project risks through strategic planning.
- Cultivated stakeholder relationships, enhancing collaborative efforts for seamless transitions.
- Facilitated change management to ensure smooth user adoption.
- Produced analytical reports on project progress and key performance indicators.
- Maintained precise documentation to support effective knowledge transfer.
- Designed and implemented RACI matrices for Business and IT teams, optimizing stakeholder engagement.

Software Developer, SAP Ariba – Bengaluru, India

Jun 2019 - Feb 2023

- Designed, implemented & tested scenarios aligned with business requirements, supporting go-live & hyper-care.
- Performed root cause analysis to resolve customer issues, achieving a 30% reduction in incident resolution time.
- Spearheaded the development and delivery of 25+ features and enhancements using Agile frameworks, improving project efficiency by 30%.
- Coordinated across 10+ teams to deliver robust technical solutions, boosting project success rate by 25%.
- Collaborated with product management, documentation, and testing teams.
- Developed custom integrations for accurate document flow and categorization.
- Designed and developed pricing conditions and improved its performance in Ariba's Guided Sourcing UI using Java, Angular, REST.
- Implemented the Purchase Info Record Auction Feature, optimizing procurement processes and increasing auction efficiency by 15%
- Led the integration of accessibility features and SAP Fiori design principles, improving user experience and inclusivity by 35%
- Acted as Scrum Master, driving Agile transformations and fostering a culture of collaboration and continuous improvement.
- Mentored and trained new team members, enhancing team capabilities.

Software Developer Associate, SAP Labs – Bengaluru, India

Aug 2017 - Jun 2019

- Gained expertise in Agile methodologies and SAP Ariba coding practices, ensuring high-quality, real-time task delivery.
- Enhanced purchase order and requisition apps using SAP UI5 while analyzing and optimizing performance by 15% for purchase info record and request for quotation apps for S/4 HANA Procurement Business Functionality.

- Developed DocuSign Simulator for NDA services for the internal Ariba teams.
- Successfully designed, developed, tested and demoed features to clients like Collins Aerospace, SAP Fieldglass, and Applied Materials Inc (AMAT) enhancing client satisfaction and driving adoption of new functionalities.
- Hackathon InnoVision 2k18 SAP Successfactors LMS Micro-Learning
 - Implemented micro-learning concept for dynamic user engagement by 25%
 - o Enhanced user experience by tagging content for easier search and recommendation.
 - Improved accessibility through the generation of audio transcripts for content processing.
- Fellowship SAP SE, Walldorf, Germany
 - Designed, developed and tested end-to-end SAP application for shared desk using SAP UI5, increasing workspace utilization by 35%.
 - Provided support in Java and API development.
 - o Participated in Innovation Week Challenge on Facial Recognition App.

Education

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani – M.Tech in Software Engineering

Aug 2017 – Aug 2021

CGPA – 9.07

Dayalbagh Educational Institute, Agra – B.Sc. in Computer Science & Mathematics *CGPA* – *9.75*

July 2014 - Jun 2017

Honors & Awards

- Received Honor, Applaud, Praise, Celebrate and Thank awards 20+ times from peers & leaders at SAP Labs and SAP Ariba for successful demo and presentations, project contributions, real-time quality and on-time deliveries.
- Volunteered AnitaB.org Women's International Tech Conference, 2019
- Organized Branding Team Event Alumni meet SAP Labs, Bengaluru
- Organized SWE mini- conference in ARIBA in Collaboration with SAP
- Program Coordinator for BITS Pilani M.Tech.
- Awarded Director's Medal for achieving highest grade point in B.Sc. Mathematics (Hons), U.G. program, 2017
- Awarded Director's Medal for achieving highest grade point in B.Sc. Computer Science and Mathematics, U.G. program, 2016
- Awarded Young Systems Scientist award in IX Indian Students Systems Conference, Agra Chapter for best paper presentation, 2015
- Awarded Director's Medal for achieving highest grade point in Intermediate (XII), 2014
- Social Service and CSR
 - o KR Puram Railway station cleaning and painting
 - Volunteered in blood donation SAP Ariba
 - SAP Ariba Run for CSR event supported by SAP Month of Service, held at ISKON Temple, donated food grains (worth INR 4 Lakhs) to the NGO (Akshaya Patra).